<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>OR Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>BLM OR Watershed Boundaries Oregon HU8 Polygon</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Portland, Oregon</pubplace><publish>OR BLM</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>WBD_HU8:
This geospatial dataset represents the 4th level (8-digit) hydrologic unit boundaries of the Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD) layer for Oregon.  It was created by dissolving boundaries from the finer resolution hydrologic units to create these broader boundaries.  See metadata for the wbd_or_poly feature class for a more complete description of the WBD.</abstract><purpose>This dataset was created to meet both national and regional requirements.  It satisfies the national requirement for a seamless hydrologic unit boundary dataset for the nation that is developed at the 1;24,000 scale.  Regionally, the dataset will be used for a number of specific purposes including resource management planning, watershed analysis,  National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) cumulative effects analysis, Endangered Species Act (ESA) consultation, biological assessments, water quality restoration plans,  water temperature assessments, watershed council project support, etc.</purpose><supplinf>ftp://ftp-fc.sc.egov.usda.gov/NCGC/products/watershed/hu-standards.pdf

The watershed and subwatershed hydrologic unit boundaries provide a uniquely identified and uniform method of subdividing large drainage areas. These smaller sized hydrologic units (up to 250,000 acres) are useful in many programs supported by the NRCS and others.</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>unknown</caldate><time>unknown</time></sngdate></timeinfo><current>publication date</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Unknown</update></status><keywords><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>Hydrologic units</themekey><themekey>Watershed Boundaries</themekey><themekey>Subwatershed Boundaries</themekey><themekey>Watershed Boundary Dataset</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>ISO 19115</themekt><themekey>inlandWaters</themekey></theme><place><placekt>BLM-State</placekt><placekey>Oregon</placekey><placekey>Idaho</placekey><placekey>Nevada</placekey><placekey>California</placekey></place><theme><themekt>BLM-Theme</themekt><themekey>Hydrography</themekey></theme></keywords><accconst>PUBLIC DATA:  None, these data are considered public domain.</accconst><useconst>
			These data are provided by Bureau of Land Management (BLM) “as is” and may contain errors or omissions.  The User assumes the entire risk associated with its use of these data and bears all responsibility in determining whether these data are fit for the User’s intended use.

			The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived, and both scale and accuracy may vary across the data set.  These data may not have the accuracy, resolution, completeness, timeliness, or other characteristics appropriate for applications that potential users of the data may contemplate.  The User is encouraged to carefully consider the content of the metadata file associated with these data.  These data are neither legal documents nor land surveys, and must not be used as such.  Official records may be referenced at most BLM offices.  Please report any errors in the data to the BLM office from which it was obtained.

			The BLM should be cited as the data source in any products derived from these data.   Any Users wishing to modify the data should describe the types of modifications they have performed.  The User should not misrepresent the data, nor imply that changes made were approved or endorsed by BLM.  This data may be updated by the BLM without notification.
		</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Dan Wickwire / Ian Reid</cntper><cntorg>OR BLM / OR NRCS</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Oregon WBD State Coordinators</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>Oregon</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>503-808-6272 / 503-414-3015</cntvoice><cntemail>dwickwir@or.blm.gov / ian.reid@or.usda.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac><native>Windows_NT, 4.0, Intel ARC/INFO version 7.1.2</native><crossref><citeinfo><origin>BLM</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>Hydrologic Unit Boundaries Oregon</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><onlink>http://hydro.reo.gov</onlink></citeinfo></crossref></idinfo><dataqual><logic>Coverage built for polygon topology. There are no overshoots or undershoot or label errors.</logic><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>PNW Hydrography Framework Partnership and NRCS</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>Draft hydrologic unit boundaries</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><othercit>The PNW Hydrography Framework Partnership is comprised of the BLM, US Forest Service (USFS), State of Oregon, and State of Washington.</othercit><onlink>http://hydro.reo.gov</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20080527</caldate><time>unknown</time></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>publication date</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>PNW-WBD</srccitea><srccontr>Polygons, Arcs &amp; Attributes</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>PNW Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) Partner agencies originally delineated hydrologic unit boundaries to meet specific agency requirements.  

The PNWHF Partnership initiated a workshop-oriented process whereby agreed-upon hydrologic boundaries were accepted or delineated using 1:24,000 scale Digital Raster Graphics.  A number of new Hydrological Unit Boundaries were also delineated using flow lines and basins computed from 10- and 30-meter horizontal resolution Digital Elevation data based on flow derived from the elevation grid to determine potential pour points. This workshop process resulted in a seamless hydrologic boundary dataset for Oregon.  

The PNWHF dataset was made available via its website for operational edits.  PNWHF Partners downloaded the dataset, edited boundaries and attribution, and submitted the updated dataset back to the PNWHF server.  

The dataset was frozen prior to submittal to the review and edit process, the precursor to NRCS certification.</procdesc><srcused>DEM30</srcused><srcused>DRG</srcused><procdate>2002</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Added the following attribute fields to support the pre NRCS certification review and edit project:

EDIT_TYPE - Type of edits that took place.

NEW_ACRES-  Change in acres after edit.

HUC_10_TYPE - Fifth Level Hydrologic Unit Type

HUC_10_MOD - Fifth Level Hydrologic Unit Modifications

HUC_12_TYPE - Sixth Level Hydrologic Unit Type

HUC_12_MOD - Sixth Level Hydrologic Unit Modifications

HU_10_NAME

HU_12_NAME

Dropped the following attribute fields:

HUC_TYPE

HUC_MOD</procdesc><procdate>2006</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Northrop Grumman/BLM</cntorg><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>OR</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>503-808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>The Pacific Northwest HU boundary dataset was broken up into workareas and provided to USGS from 1 (PNW1)  through 15 (PNW15) according to a schedule defined by all PNW partners and USGS. The PNW#'s were extracted and sent to the USGS for update and edit as a precursor to national NRCS certification.</procdesc><procdate>20060126</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>Northrop Grumman/OR BLM</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>OR</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(503) 808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>USGS  refined the PNWHF Hydrologic Unit Boundaries and required attribution using consistent, reproducible methods that meet the "Federal Standards for Delineations of Hydrologic Unit Boundaries".  It was agreed that the Digital Raster Graphic (DRG) would be the primary source used for delineating boundaries.  Arc, polygon and attribute adjustments were made to each PNW#. Changes were limited in the dataset to only those modifications that were needed to meet the national guidelines.   Replacement of boundary lines or HU names that already meet the standard were to be avoided.  There were two reviews by PNW Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) before a final was delivered back to PNWHF by USGS. After each review USGS incorporated changes that were identified and agreed-upon during the review process.</procdesc><procdate>2006</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Kimberly Jones</cntper><cntorg>USGS</cntorg></cntperp><cntemail>kjones@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>The final datasets returned from  USGS were assembled to make the PNW distribution coverage and the final Oregon dataset for certification.  In the Final Oregon Dataset attributes fields were updated to to meet the national standards for both Arcs and Polgons.  All Seventh field huc attributes, Arcs and labels were deleted from this final dataset.</procdesc><procdate>20080527</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM Oregon State Office/Northrop Grumman</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>503-808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>META_ID: OR03
The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations.  The changes included small boundary adjustments that result in a better match with NHD, an updated 12 digit HU boundary derived from LiDAR source data, and WBD HU name changes.  Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. 
The WBD boundary was changed in areas where the NHD was crossing the WBD boundary. In these instances, the NHD source was the PNWHF dataset and not the DRG.  Subwatershed 171002030602 was completely replaced using Oregon Department of Forestry's (ODF)  boundaries that were derived from LiDAR source data.  This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground. In several locations the old WBD boundary crossed stream channels indicated on the DEM. ODF used a 5 foot contour layer, derived from the LiDAR DEM, to delineate the boundary changes. Updates to the WBD boundaries for this subwatershed were performed using the ESRI Reshape Featuretool.  This update affected six adjoining 12 digit HU all within the same 10 digit HU.
Name changes were submitted at the 10 and 12 digit HU level. The attributes HU_10_NAME and HU_12_NAME were updated depending on the change request.
USGS at this time made updates to WBD boundary adding Water HU's for the Oregon coast.</procdesc><procdate>20100713</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OSO</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>OR</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(503) 808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><srcused>NHD24</srcused><srcused>LiDAR</srcused><srcused>DRG24</srcused></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Once the edits were certified the OR WBD feature class was downloaded from the Geospatial Data Gateway and was used to make this polygon feature class.  The OR_WBD was dissolved using the fields HUC_8 and HU_8_NAME also using the sum of Acres in the statistics field to get the acres for each polygon. The output from the dissolve comand is a 4th level (8 digit)  subwatershed feature class that was used to load the data into this feature class. The field HU_8_NAME was added to the feature class and not part of the certified WBD_OR Dataset.</procdesc><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OSO</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>503-808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><procdate>20110228</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City</cntorg></cntorgp></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>META_ID: OR04 NHDPlus updates and OR05 Canadian border updates and Ocean updates.
USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City, Utah:  
HUC Level changes; Line Mods (SL for shoreline, PL for Playa); 
State updates (CAN for Canada instead of Province codes); DS codes (OCEAN, CLOSED BASIN, CLOSED BAS, CANADA)</procdesc><srcused>NHD</srcused><procdate>201101</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City</cntorg></cntorgp></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>META_ID: OR06
Edits by USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City, Utah: 
The Line Mods, HU_Level, Linesource, DS codes and states were checked.</procdesc><procdate>20110322</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>USGS Nevada</cntorg></cntorgp></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>META_ID: OR07
Edits by USGS Nevada; edits to codes or downstream codes.</procdesc><procdate>201106</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OR/WA</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>(503) 808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>META_ID OR08:
The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations.  The changes include updated 12 digit HU boundaries derived from LiDAR source data.  Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. 
Subwatersheds 171002030601, 171002030602, and 171003080106 were delineated using 10 foot, and 3 foot contour layers that were derived from a LiDAR DEM.  This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground.  In most instances the boundary just needed to be moved to the ridge tops. This did not affect the overall size or the outlet of the subwatershed.  However, in subwatershed 171003080106 the LiDAR source data did highlight that the outlet needed to be changed. This change affected two adjacent subwatersheds 171003080105 and 171003080107.  The changes to the outlets were reviewed and accepted by the state stewards. In all but 171002030601, the adjoining subwatersheds were affected by this update.  Subwateshed 71002030601 was updated in the last Oregon submittal and not all of the adjoining subwatershed's arcs needed to be updated. Updates to the WBD boundaries for these subwatersheds were performed using the ESRI Modify Edge Tool in ArcMAP 10.0 on the ArcGIS 9.2 geodatabase.</procdesc><procdate>20111205</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OR/WA</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>(503) 808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>Once the edits were certified the OR WBD feature class was downloaded from the Geospatial Data Gateway and was used to make this polygon feature class.  The OR_WBD was dissolved using the fields HUC_8 and HU_8_NAME also using the sum of Acres in the statistics field to get the acres for each polygon. The output from the dissolve comand is a 4th level (8 digit)  subwatershed feature class that was used to load the data into this feature class. The field HU_8_NAME was added to the feature class and not part of the certified WBD_OR Dataset.</procdesc><procdate>20121010</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OR/WA</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>503-808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><srcused>LiDAR</srcused><srcused>NHD24</srcused><procdesc>Meta_ID: OR09 The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations.  The changes include 4 digit changes to the Columbia River/Willamette River area, a multiple 4 digit line change to LiDAR , updated 12 digit HU boundaries derived from LiDAR source data, a 12 digit boundary change from a field verified source and 1 Watershed and 4 Subwatershed name changes.  Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. 
The portion of the Lower Willamette 8 digit HU (17090012) that included the Columbia River was moved into 1708 to connect the Columbia River into a single 4 digit HU.  Before the edit this segment of the Columbia River was disconnected from the rest of the Lower Columbia 4 digit HU (1708). This portion of the 8 digit HU 17090012 was moved into the 8 digit HU 17080003. This update also took place in Washington.
A change was made to a 4 digit HU line between subbasins 17080001, 17070105, and 17070306. The updated line was moved to 10 foot contours derived from a LiDAR DEM. The boundary was moved to the ridge tops and did not affect the overall size or the outlet of these subbasins.  The move was requested to also make a change to the county lines between Multnomah, Clackamas ad Hood River counties.
The PNWHF has acquired LiDAR for the Little North Santiam River watershed and the Big Creek Subwastershed and is updating the NHD and WBD to the acquired LiDAR.  Little North Santiam River watershed (1709000505) and its 5 Subwatersheds were delineated from 10, 5, and 2 foot contour layers that were generated from a LiDAR DEM. This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground. The movement of the lines does not affect the overall size or outlet of the Watershed. Most of the changes were moving the line to the ridge tops.  However, the LiDAR source data did highlight that a change to the outlet of the subwatershed Upper Little North Santiam River (170900050503) had to be altered.  The change to the outlet was reviewed and accepted by the state stewards.  Big Creek subwatershed (171003050109) was delineated from 10 and 5 foot contours that were generated from a LiDAR DEM. This LiDAR based DEM also highlighted areas where the WBD did accurately reflect the condition on the ground.  The only movement of the boundary was moving it to the ridge tops and the overall size and outlet did not change.
A line edit was made between Subwatersheds (12 digit HU’s)  170502010205 Benson Creek and 1705010206 Crouse Creek – Snake River. The edits are based on the existence of a culvert and stream diversions into ditches.  On-site evaluation indicates that the drainage changes caused by the man-made features are essentially permanent.  The NHD shows a connector under the freeway does not exist based on a on-the-ground inspection. The line was moved to incorporate these findings.
The multiple name changes did not affect the geometry to the watershed or any of the subwatersheds.  The changes include Burnt River (1705020208) to Dixie Creek – Burnt River, Pine Tree Ridge Creek (170502010203) to Love Reservoir, Trickle Creek-Deep Creek (170900110604) to Tickle Creek-Deep Creek, Headwaters North Summit River (170703040304) to Headwaters North Fork Crooked River, and Peterson Creek-North Fork Summit River 170703040308 to Peterson Creek-North Fork Crooked River.
</procdesc><srcused>DRG24</srcused><procdate>20130110</procdate></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Bryant Mecklem</cntper><cntorg>BLM OR/WA</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntvoice>503-808-6506</cntvoice><cntemail>bmecklem@blm.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></proccont><procdesc>Once the edits were nationally certified the edits were pasted back into the PNW copy of the ORWA_WBD polygon feature class. The polygon feature class was clipped out for each state.  The WBD was dissolved and Acres summed to make each HU level feature class. </procdesc><procdate>20130115</procdate></procstep></lineage><cloud>0</cloud></dataqual><spdoinfo><indspref>Oregon, Washington, California, Idaho</indspref><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf/></spdoinfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Bureau of Land Management</cntorg><cntper>Eric Hiebenthal</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>OR</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>503-808-6340</cntvoice><cntfax>503-808-6419</cntfax><cntemail>ehiebent@blm.gov</cntemail><cntpos>GIS Data Management Specialist</cntpos><cntinst>contact instructions</cntinst></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>
				The BLM assumes no responsibility for errors or omissions.  No warranty is made by the BLM as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data for individual use or aggregate use with other data; nor shall the act of distribution to contractors, partners, or beyond, constitute any such warranty for individual or aggregate data use with other data.  Although these data have been processed successfully on computers of BLM, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made by BLM regarding the use of these data on any other system, or for general or scientific purposes, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.  In no event shall the BLM have any liability whatsoever for payment of any consequential, incidental, indirect, special, or tort damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, any loss of profits arising out of the use or reliance on the geographic data or arising out of the delivery, installation, operation, or support by BLM.
			</distliab><stdorder><fees>Contact distributor.</fees><ordering>Data are only available through the Oregon/Washington State office of the Bureau of Land Management.</ordering></stdorder><resdesc>Offline Data</resdesc></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20060113</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Bureau of Land Management, Oregon State Office</cntorg><cntper>Roger Mills</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 2965</address><city>Portland</city><state>OR</state><postal>97208</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(503) 808-6340</cntvoice><cnttdd>tdd/tty phone</cnttdd><cntfax>(503) 808-6419</cntfax><cntemail>r2mills@blm.gov</cntemail><hours>8:00-4:00</hours><cntinst>None</cntinst></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metac>None</metac><metuc>None</metuc><metsi><metsc>Unclassified</metsc></metsi><metrd>20130124</metrd></metainfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdContact><rpIndName>Roger Mills</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Bureau of Land Management, Oregon State Office</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>(503) 808-6340</voiceNum><voiceNum tddtty="True">tdd/tty phone</voiceNum><faxNum>(503) 808-6419</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O. Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>OR</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>r2mills@blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>8:00-4:00</cntHours><cntInstr>None</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdDateSt>20060113</mdDateSt><mdStanName>ArcGIS Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer>1.0</mdStanVer><distInfo><distributor><distorCont><rpIndName>Eric Hiebenthal</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Bureau of Land Management</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Data Management Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6340</voiceNum><faxNum>503-808-6419</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>OR</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>ehiebent@blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntInstr>contact instructions</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="005"/></role></distorCont><distorOrdPrc><resFees>Contact distributor.</resFees><ordInstr>Data are only available through the Oregon/Washington State office of the Bureau of Land Management.</ordInstr></distorOrdPrc></distributor><distFormat><formatName>File Geodatabase Feature Class</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>BLM OR Watershed Boundaries Oregon HU8 Polygon</resTitle><date><pubDate date="unknown"/></date><citRespParty><rpOrgName>OR Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty><rpOrgName>OR BLM</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>Portland, Oregon</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></idCitation><idAbs>WBD_HU8: This geospatial dataset represents the 4th level (8-digit) hydrologic unit boundaries of the Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD) layer for Oregon. It was created by dissolving boundaries from the finer resolution hydrologic units to create these broader boundaries. See metadata for the wbd_or_poly feature class for a more complete description of the WBD.</idAbs><idPurp>This dataset was created to meet both national and regional requirements. It satisfies the national requirement for a seamless hydrologic unit boundary dataset for the nation that is developed at the 1;24,000 scale. Regionally, the dataset will be used for a number of specific purposes including resource management planning, watershed analysis, National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) cumulative effects analysis, Endangered Species Act (ESA) consultation, biological assessments, water quality restoration plans, water temperature assessments, watershed council project support, etc.</idPurp><idStatus><ProgCd value="001"/></idStatus><idPoC><rpIndName>Dan Wickwire / Ian Reid</rpIndName><rpOrgName>OR BLM / OR NRCS</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Oregon WBD State Coordinators</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6272 / 503-414-3015</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O. Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>Oregon</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>dwickwir@or.blm.gov / ian.reid@or.usda.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></idPoC><resMaint><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="012"/></maintFreq></resMaint><placeKeys><keyword>Idaho</keyword><keyword>Oregon</keyword><keyword>Nevada</keyword><keyword>California</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>BLM-State</resTitle></thesaName></placeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>Hydrography</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>BLM-Theme</resTitle></thesaName></themeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>Subwatershed Boundaries</keyword><keyword>Watershed Boundaries</keyword><keyword>Watershed Boundary Dataset</keyword><keyword>Hydrologic units</keyword></themeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>inlandWaters</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>ISO 19115</resTitle></thesaName></themeKeys><searchKeys><keyword>Subwatershed Boundaries</keyword><keyword>Watershed Boundaries</keyword><keyword>Idaho</keyword><keyword>Oregon</keyword><keyword>Nevada</keyword><keyword>Watershed Boundary Dataset</keyword><keyword>California</keyword><keyword>Hydrologic units</keyword><keyword>Hydrography</keyword><keyword>inlandWaters</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><LegConsts><useLimit>The BLM assumes no responsibility for errors or omissions. No warranty is made by the BLM as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data for individual use or aggregate use with other data; nor shall the act of distribution to contractors, partners, or beyond, constitute any such warranty for individual or aggregate data use with other data. Although these data have been processed successfully on computers of BLM, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made by BLM regarding the use of these data on any other system, or for general or scientific purposes, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty. In no event shall the BLM have any liability whatsoever for payment of any consequential, incidental, indirect, special, or tort damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, any loss of profits arising out of the use or reliance on the geographic data or arising out of the delivery, installation, operation, or support by BLM.</useLimit><othConsts>PUBLIC DATA: None, these data are considered public domain.</othConsts></LegConsts></resConst><resConst><Consts><useLimit>These data are provided by Bureau of Land Management (BLM) “as is” and may contain errors or omissions. The User assumes the entire risk associated with its use of these data and bears all responsibility in determining whether these data are fit for the User’s intended use. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived, and both scale and accuracy may vary across the data set. These data may not have the accuracy, resolution, completeness, timeliness, or other characteristics appropriate for applications that potential users of the data may contemplate. The User is encouraged to carefully consider the content of the metadata file associated with these data. These data are neither legal documents nor land surveys, and must not be used as such. Official records may be referenced at most BLM offices. Please report any errors in the data to the BLM office from which it was obtained. The BLM should be cited as the data source in any products derived from these data. Any Users wishing to modify the data should describe the types of modifications they have performed. The User should not misrepresent the data, nor imply that changes made were approved or endorsed by BLM. This data may be updated by the BLM without notification.</useLimit></Consts></resConst><aggrInfo><aggrDSName><resTitle>Hydrologic Unit Boundaries Oregon</resTitle><date><pubDate date="unknown"/></date><citRespParty><rpOrgName>BLM</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm><citOnlineRes><linkage>http://hydro.reo.gov</linkage></citOnlineRes></aggrDSName><assocType><AscTypeCd value="001"/></assocType></aggrInfo><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001"/></spatRpType><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA"/></dataLang><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="012"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="003"/></tpCat><envirDesc>Windows_NT, 4.0, Intel ARC/INFO version 7.1.2</envirDesc><dataExt><exDesc>publication date</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Instant><tmPosition date="unknown" time="unknown"/></TM_Instant></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle><geoEle/></dataExt><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox><westBL>-125</westBL><eastBL>-116</eastBL><southBL>40.5</southBL><northBL>46.5</northBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><suppInfo>ftp://ftp-fc.sc.egov.usda.gov/NCGC/products/watershed/hu-standards.pdf The watershed and subwatershed hydrologic unit boundaries provide a uniquely identified and uniform method of subdividing large drainage areas. These smaller sized hydrologic units (up to 250,000 acres) are useful in many programs supported by the NRCS and others.</suppInfo><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode>1</exTypeCode><westBL>-124.703833</westBL><eastBL>-115.958474</eastBL><northBL>46.514440</northBL><southBL>40.760092</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt></dataIdInfo><mdMaint><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="012"/></maintFreq><maintNote>Last metadata review date: 20130124</maintNote></mdMaint><mdConst><SecConsts><class><ClasscationCd value="001"/></class></SecConsts></mdConst><dqInfo><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope><report type="DQTopConsis"><evalMethDesc>Coverage built for polygon topology. There are no overshoots or undershoot or label errors.</evalMethDesc></report><report type="DQConcConsis"><measDesc>Coverage built for polygon topology. There are no overshoots or undershoot or label errors.</measDesc></report><dataLineage><prcStep><stepDesc>The Pacific Northwest HU boundary dataset was broken up into workareas and provided to USGS from 1 (PNW1) through 15 (PNW15) according to a schedule defined by all PNW partners and USGS. The PNW#'s were extracted and sent to the USGS for update and edit as a precursor to national NRCS certification.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2006-01-26</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Northrop Grumman/OR BLM</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>(503) 808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O. Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>OR</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>PNW Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) Partner agencies originally delineated hydrologic unit boundaries to meet specific agency requirements. The PNWHF Partnership initiated a workshop-oriented process whereby agreed-upon hydrologic boundaries were accepted or delineated using 1:24,000 scale Digital Raster Graphics. A number of new Hydrological Unit Boundaries were also delineated using flow lines and basins computed from 10- and 30-meter horizontal resolution Digital Elevation data based on flow derived from the elevation grid to determine potential pour points. This workshop process resulted in a seamless hydrologic boundary dataset for Oregon. The PNWHF dataset was made available via its website for operational edits. PNWHF Partners downloaded the dataset, edited boundaries and attribution, and submitted the updated dataset back to the PNWHF server. The dataset was frozen prior to submittal to the review and edit process, the precursor to NRCS certification.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2002-01-01</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>DEM30</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>DRG</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>META_ID: OR03 The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations. The changes included small boundary adjustments that result in a better match with NHD, an updated 12 digit HU boundary derived from LiDAR source data, and WBD HU name changes. Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. The WBD boundary was changed in areas where the NHD was crossing the WBD boundary. In these instances, the NHD source was the PNWHF dataset and not the DRG. Subwatershed 171002030602 was completely replaced using Oregon Department of Forestry's (ODF) boundaries that were derived from LiDAR source data. This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground. In several locations the old WBD boundary crossed stream channels indicated on the DEM. ODF used a 5 foot contour layer, derived from the LiDAR DEM, to delineate the boundary changes. Updates to the WBD boundaries for this subwatershed were performed using the ESRI Reshape Featuretool. This update affected six adjoining 12 digit HU all within the same 10 digit HU. Name changes were submitted at the 10 and 12 digit HU level. The attributes HU_10_NAME and HU_12_NAME were updated depending on the change request. USGS at this time made updates to WBD boundary adding Water HU's for the Oregon coast.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2010-07-13</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OSO</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>(503) 808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O. Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>OR</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>LiDAR</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>DRG24</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>NHD24</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>META_ID: OR07 Edits by USGS Nevada; edits to codes or downstream codes.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2011-06-01</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpOrgName>USGS Nevada</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>META_ID: OR06 Edits by USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City, Utah: The Line Mods, HU_Level, Linesource, DS codes and states were checked.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2011-03-22</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpOrgName>USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>META_ID: OR04 NHDPlus updates and OR05 Canadian border updates and Ocean updates. USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City, Utah: HUC Level changes; Line Mods (SL for shoreline, PL for Playa); State updates (CAN for Canada instead of Province codes); DS codes (OCEAN, CLOSED BASIN, CLOSED BAS, CANADA)</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2011-01-01</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpOrgName>USGS Water Science Center in Salt Lake City</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>NHD</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Once the edits were nationally certified the edits were pasted back into the PNW copy of the ORWA_WBD polygon feature class. The polygon feature class was clipped out for each state. The WBD was dissolved and Acres summed to make each HU level feature class.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2013-01-15</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OR/WA</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Meta_ID: OR09 The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations. The changes include 4 digit changes to the Columbia River/Willamette River area, a multiple 4 digit line change to LiDAR , updated 12 digit HU boundaries derived from LiDAR source data, a 12 digit boundary change from a field verified source and 1 Watershed and 4 Subwatershed name changes. Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. The portion of the Lower Willamette 8 digit HU (17090012) that included the Columbia River was moved into 1708 to connect the Columbia River into a single 4 digit HU. Before the edit this segment of the Columbia River was disconnected from the rest of the Lower Columbia 4 digit HU (1708). This portion of the 8 digit HU 17090012 was moved into the 8 digit HU 17080003. This update also took place in Washington. A change was made to a 4 digit HU line between subbasins 17080001, 17070105, and 17070306. The updated line was moved to 10 foot contours derived from a LiDAR DEM. The boundary was moved to the ridge tops and did not affect the overall size or the outlet of these subbasins. The move was requested to also make a change to the county lines between Multnomah, Clackamas ad Hood River counties. The PNWHF has acquired LiDAR for the Little North Santiam River watershed and the Big Creek Subwastershed and is updating the NHD and WBD to the acquired LiDAR. Little North Santiam River watershed (1709000505) and its 5 Subwatersheds were delineated from 10, 5, and 2 foot contour layers that were generated from a LiDAR DEM. This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground. The movement of the lines does not affect the overall size or outlet of the Watershed. Most of the changes were moving the line to the ridge tops. However, the LiDAR source data did highlight that a change to the outlet of the subwatershed Upper Little North Santiam River (170900050503) had to be altered. The change to the outlet was reviewed and accepted by the state stewards. Big Creek subwatershed (171003050109) was delineated from 10 and 5 foot contours that were generated from a LiDAR DEM. This LiDAR based DEM also highlighted areas where the WBD did accurately reflect the condition on the ground. The only movement of the boundary was moving it to the ridge tops and the overall size and outlet did not change. A line edit was made between Subwatersheds (12 digit HU’s) 170502010205 Benson Creek and 1705010206 Crouse Creek – Snake River. The edits are based on the existence of a culvert and stream diversions into ditches. On-site evaluation indicates that the drainage changes caused by the man-made features are essentially permanent. The NHD shows a connector under the freeway does not exist based on a on-the-ground inspection. The line was moved to incorporate these findings. The multiple name changes did not affect the geometry to the watershed or any of the subwatersheds. The changes include Burnt River (1705020208) to Dixie Creek – Burnt River, Pine Tree Ridge Creek (170502010203) to Love Reservoir, Trickle Creek-Deep Creek (170900110604) to Tickle Creek-Deep Creek, Headwaters North Summit River (170703040304) to Headwaters North Fork Crooked River, and Peterson Creek-North Fork Summit River 170703040308 to Peterson Creek-North Fork Crooked River.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2013-01-10</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OR/WA</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>LiDAR</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>DRG24</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>NHD24</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Added the following attribute fields to support the pre NRCS certification review and edit project: EDIT_TYPE - Type of edits that took place. NEW_ACRES- Change in acres after edit. HUC_10_TYPE - Fifth Level Hydrologic Unit Type HUC_10_MOD - Fifth Level Hydrologic Unit Modifications HUC_12_TYPE - Sixth Level Hydrologic Unit Type HUC_12_MOD - Sixth Level Hydrologic Unit Modifications HU_10_NAME HU_12_NAME Dropped the following attribute fields: HUC_TYPE HUC_MOD</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2006-01-01</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Northrop Grumman/BLM</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="postal"><delPoint>P.O. Box 2965</delPoint><city>Portland</city><adminArea>OR</adminArea><postCode>97208</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Once the edits were certified the OR WBD feature class was downloaded from the Geospatial Data Gateway and was used to make this polygon feature class. The OR_WBD was dissolved using the fields HUC_8 and HU_8_NAME also using the sum of Acres in the statistics field to get the acres for each polygon. The output from the dissolve comand is a 4th level (8 digit) subwatershed feature class that was used to load the data into this feature class. The field HU_8_NAME was added to the feature class and not part of the certified WBD_OR Dataset.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2011-02-28</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OSO</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Once the edits were certified the OR WBD feature class was downloaded from the Geospatial Data Gateway and was used to make this polygon feature class. The OR_WBD was dissolved using the fields HUC_8 and HU_8_NAME also using the sum of Acres in the statistics field to get the acres for each polygon. The output from the dissolve comand is a 4th level (8 digit) subwatershed feature class that was used to load the data into this feature class. The field HU_8_NAME was added to the feature class and not part of the certified WBD_OR Dataset.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2012-10-10</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OR/WA</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>(503) 808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>USGS refined the PNWHF Hydrologic Unit Boundaries and required attribution using consistent, reproducible methods that meet the "Federal Standards for Delineations of Hydrologic Unit Boundaries". It was agreed that the Digital Raster Graphic (DRG) would be the primary source used for delineating boundaries. Arc, polygon and attribute adjustments were made to each PNW#. Changes were limited in the dataset to only those modifications that were needed to meet the national guidelines. Replacement of boundary lines or HU names that already meet the standard were to be avoided. There were two reviews by PNW Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) before a final was delivered back to PNWHF by USGS. After each review USGS incorporated changes that were identified and agreed-upon during the review process.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2006-01-01</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Kimberly Jones</rpIndName><rpOrgName>USGS</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><eMailAdd>kjones@usgs.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>META_ID OR08: The Oregon WBD dataset was updated to incorporate changes submitted by Pacific Northwest Hydrography Framework (PNWHF) partner organizations. The changes include updated 12 digit HU boundaries derived from LiDAR source data. Each of these proposed changes were reviewed by affected stewards for validity. Subwatersheds 171002030601, 171002030602, and 171003080106 were delineated using 10 foot, and 3 foot contour layers that were derived from a LiDAR DEM. This LiDAR based DEM highlighted several areas where the WBD did not accurately reflect the condition on the ground. In most instances the boundary just needed to be moved to the ridge tops. This did not affect the overall size or the outlet of the subwatershed. However, in subwatershed 171003080106 the LiDAR source data did highlight that the outlet needed to be changed. This change affected two adjacent subwatersheds 171003080105 and 171003080107. The changes to the outlets were reviewed and accepted by the state stewards. In all but 171002030601, the adjoining subwatersheds were affected by this update. Subwateshed 71002030601 was updated in the last Oregon submittal and not all of the adjoining subwatershed's arcs needed to be updated. Updates to the WBD boundaries for these subwatersheds were performed using the ESRI Modify Edge Tool in ArcMAP 10.0 on the ArcGIS 9.2 geodatabase.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2011-12-05</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM OR/WA</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>(503) 808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>The final datasets returned from USGS were assembled to make the PNW distribution coverage and the final Oregon dataset for certification. In the Final Oregon Dataset attributes fields were updated to to meet the national standards for both Arcs and Polgons. All Seventh field huc attributes, Arcs and labels were deleted from this final dataset.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2008-05-27</stepDateTm><stepProc><rpIndName>Bryant Mecklem</rpIndName><rpOrgName>BLM Oregon State Office/Northrop Grumman</rpOrgName><rpPosName>GIS Specialist</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>503-808-6506</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><eMailAdd>bmecklem@or.blm.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="009"/></role></stepProc></prcStep><dataSource><srcDesc>Polygons, Arcs &amp; Attributes</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Draft hydrologic unit boundaries</resTitle><resAltTitle>PNW-WBD</resAltTitle><date><pubDate date="unknown"/></date><citRespParty><rpOrgName>PNW Hydrography Framework Partnership and NRCS</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm><otherCitDet>The PNW Hydrography Framework Partnership is comprised of the BLM, US Forest Service (USFS), State of Oregon, and State of Washington.</otherCitDet><citOnlineRes><linkage>http://hydro.reo.gov</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn><srcExt><exDesc>publication date</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Instant><tmPosition time="unknown">2008-05-27</tmPosition></TM_Instant></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle></srcExt></dataSource></dataLineage></dqInfo><spatRepInfo><Indref>Oregon, Washington, California, Idaho</Indref><VectSpatRep><geometObjs><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002"/></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt>92</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001"/></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdHrLvName>dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="4269"/><idCodeSpace>EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion>8.2.6</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>WBD_HU8</enttypl></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC_8</attrlabl></attr><attr><attrlabl>HU_8_NAME</attrlabl></attr><attr><attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE_Area</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20210303</CreaDate><CreaTime>08050600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce></Esri></metadata>
